A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Letters, 1917-1957
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
James Branch Cabell Letters, 1917-1957
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-c
This collection consists of 62 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 21 April 1959.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains letters of James Branch Cabell, 1917-1957. To Sinclair Lewis, Cabell gives high praise for Main Street and The Job. Cabell also discusses American writers in general; Joseph Hergesheimer; and his own work, including The Cream of the Jest, and the censorship which Jurgen received. To Carl Van Vechten, Cabell sends copies of several books, including The Majors and Their Marriages, Jurgen, The High Place, The Silver stallion, Music from Behind the Moon, and The First Gentlemen of America. Cabell also relates health, birthday, and social news to Van Vechten; discusses Van Vechten's writings regarding Joseph Hergesheimer; and announces his marriage to Margaret Freeman.
These letters are on microfilm (M-1530), from originals in the Yale University Library. They are in the order in which they appear on the microfilm.
Contents List
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Sinclair Lewis 26 November 1917, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Sinclair Lewis 9 July 1920, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Sinclair Lewis 7 August 1920, AL, first page only, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Sinclair Lewis 18 October 1920, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to "Hal" [Lewis] 29 April 1921, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to "Hal" [Lewis] 17 June 1922, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to "Hal" [Lewis] 21 September 1922, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to "Hal" [Lewis] 29 October 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 15 March 1919, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 22 March 1919, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 28 September 1921, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 1 December 1923, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 29 December 1923, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 27 January 1925, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 15 May 1926, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten July 1 1926, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 15 December 1928, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 20 April 1929, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 19 April 1930, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 30 January 1932, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 26 February 1932, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 16 April 1932, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 30 January 1933, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 20 January 1933, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 7 March 1934, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 14 April 1934, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 20 April 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 17 April 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 5 May 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 9 October 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 4 December 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 18 February 1936, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 17 April 1936, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 28 October 1936, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 16 April 1938, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 20 April 1941, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 10 January 1942, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 31 January 1942, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 11 January 1943, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 27 August 1943, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 26 July 1946, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 9 August 1946, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 30 March 1947, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 2 January 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 6 March 1946, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 20 March 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 8 May 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 22 May 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 27 May 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 2 November 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 28 December 1948, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 27 February 1949, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 23 April 1949, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from Margaret and James Cabell to Fania and Carl Van Vechten 18 June 1950, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 1 August 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 6 August 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 17 April 1951, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 29 January 1952, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 14 February 1952, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 1 August 1935, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 17 April 1954, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 16 April 1956, TLS, 1 page
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Vechten 16 April 1957, TLS, 1 page